and the territory of Russia will somehow change Yes, the
а территория России как-то изменится Да
territory of Russia, look. As a result of
территория России смотри В результате
the defeat, you already have a lot of
поражения у вас уже идут очень много
different destructive
разных деструктивных таких
state things going on, these
государственных вещей вот эти
national battalions, the Chechens have
национальные Батальоны там у чеченцев
their own national battalion, the Tatars have their own, the
свой национальный батальон у татар свой
Bashkortos have their own, you will have a conditional
у башкорто в свой у вас будет условно
revolution there or so  Or so there
там или революция так Или так брожение
will be fermentation, so Russia will break up into different
будет так Россия распадётся на разные
states Hello Good afternoon I am
государства Здравствуйте Добрый день Я
from Ukraine, the city of Khmelnitsky And where do
из Украины город Хмельницкий А вы откуда
I see you from I am from Russia from the Krasnodar Territory
я вижу Я с России с Краснодарского края
We have already communicated  were one way or
Мы с вами уже общались были так или
another no one way or another that there
иначе нет так или иначе что там
you support the special operation of course
спецоперацию поддерживаете конечно
little brother Well it has changed since then
братишка потихоньку Что ж сменилось с
somehow they began to
тех пор как-то начали активнее
support more actively or not I’ll tell you this I’m in
поддерживать или нет я вам скажу так я в
politics Well give or take how your flag
политике Ну плюс-минус как ваш флаг
understands and it’s an inanimate object
понимает а он неодушевлённый предмет
You understand  yes, about the World Cup, yes, well, you
Сами понимаете да о ЧМ я Да ну вы
support the special operation. Well, damn, this is
поддерживаете спецоперацию Ну блин это
my country, how can I not support it? I
моя страна как я могу не поддерживать я
probably would have left if I hadn’t supported it,
бы наверное уехал если бы не поддерживал
and maybe I just didn’t. How exactly do you
а возможно просто не А как именно вы
support it? You can tell in what
поддерживаете можете сказать в какий
form you are  you support, well, in what form do
форме вы поддерживаете ну В какой форме
I support? Yes, but firstly, I
я поддерживаю Да но во-первых я
support our soldiers who are
поддерживаю наших солдат которые там
fighting there, giving their lives, this is definitely
воюют отдают своей жизни однозначно это
the most important Factor. Well, there is a 16,130
самый главный Фактор А ну есть 16 130
front and they send humanitarian aid there, I
фронт и туда отправляет гуманитарку я
also send it Pony ho Well, everything comes from my,
также её отправляю Поня хо Ну от моего
so to speak, pedigree  Well, that is, that’s
так сказать родословной всё Ну то есть
enough,
этого доста
yes. But for example, if, what do you think,
да А например если вот Как вы считаете
if in Russia there will be a second wave
если в России будет там вторая волна
of mobilization and you will be drafted by the military registration and enlistment office, it’s
мобилизации так и вас призовут военкомат
impossible to go to the university? Why am I
пойдёте во невозможно А почему я
still studying at the university?  And you kind of
обучаюсь ещё в университете А вы типа
understood, you're like a studio You want
понял вы типа студи Вы хотите чтобы
others to be killed while I understand, but who is
других пока убивали я понял да кого
being killed Well, I mean Well, for example, there
убивают Ну в смысле Ну например только
were just some guys from Samara talking about
что были чуваки из Самары рассказывали
how they had 89 coffins come to the city
Да как у них 89 гробов пришло в город
after the Makeevka attack on Makeevka I
после макеевского удара Макеевки Я
heard about it Well, not about  blow and about the fact
слышал про это Ну не про удар а про то
that there was a normal topic Yes, a
что там ну нормальная тема была Да
normal topic Yes, so everyone gathered for the
нормальная тема Да так собрали все на
New Year to watch this speech by
Новый год посмотреть это выступление
Putin, it was tough, it was tough on the horse The
Путина жёстко жёстко было коне Дело в
fact is that Makeyevka This  It’s not the first time
том что Макеевка Это же не первый раз
you just took Makeyevka and raised it in an
просто Макеевку ваши взяли и подняли в
information topic. And before that there was a bunch of
информационной теме А до этого ещё куча
Makeyevka,
Макеево
for example Chernobayevka or like
было например чернобаевка или как
Chernobayevka there’s a damn thing like we even
чернобаевка там вообще блин типа мы даже
Chernobayev’s operational headquarters even
чернобаев оперативный штаб даже
stopped counting that
перестали короче уже считать ту
Chernobayev at first it wasn’t fun in
чернобаев сначала е было весело в
Ukraine I know Streamer  this is flax This is
Украине есть знаю Стример это льно Это
in general so look it
во это вообще так вот то смотри
turns out If Putin signs a decree
получается Если Путин подписывает указ
that in short there is a general mobilization
что короче там всё обще мобилизация
against NATO even of students and they will take
против НАТО даже студентов и вот возьмут
you for what are you  you will die in
тебя за что ты будешь умирать в
Ukraine in Ukraine No, I will
Украине в Украине Нет я пойду в том
only go if they really come to my land,
случае только если реально на мою землю
no, look at it Wait until the
зайдут нет так смотри Подожди когда тебя
state sends you, it won’t
государство будет отправлять оно же не
ask about yours, not yours So
будет спрашивать на твою не на твою Вот
they say, come on Kherson - This is your
они говорят всё давай Херсон - Это твоя
Land In short, let’s go  go there to fight Kherson -
Земля Короче пошёл туда воевать Херсон -
This is my land Well, if this is really my
Это моя земля Ну если это моя реально
Land, the referendum was held right there Well,
Земля там же референдум прошёл пра Ну
yes, yes, I’ll say that this is your Land, everything And
вот да да скажу что это твоя Земля всё И
you, I’ll get there, I’ll stop
теб вот дотуда я дойду остановлюсь
further, the referendum won’t  carried out and will
дальше референдум не проводил и буду
not wait Well, look, Kherson is now
ждать не Ну ты смотри вот Херсон сейчас
occupied by Ukrainian troops, they
занят украинскими войсками вот тебя
’ll throw you into sailing through the Dnieper to storm Kherson.
кинут На штурм Херсона через Днепр
Well, look, they won’t throw me at me, I don’t have
плыть Ну смотрите меня не кинут у меня
any military training, that’s it.
никакой военной подготовки не вот Вот
Yes, but there will be such a
именно Да вот а вот будет такая
mobilization that even without military
мобилизация что даже без военной
training.  They will throw you because
подготовки вот Будут кидать потому что
everything will be so bad already, but I don’t
уже так всё плохо будет да что плохо
understand well, I’m sitting drinking tea, no. So
понимаю я сижу пью чай нет Так у тебя у
you’re doing well now. I say the
тебя сейчас хорошо Я говорю у армии
Russian army is bad, that is, everyone has it,
российской плохо то есть она у всех она
look, it’s because of  the fact that it
на смотрите она из-за того что она там
began to end there near Kiev
начала заканчиваться под Киевом
Kharkov in Kherson And so on, so the
Харьковом в Херсоне И так дальше так
problems began, so because of this
начались проблемы так из-за этого
they did mobilization like this near
сделали мобилизацию вот эту так под
Kiev Where where 3 days ended
Киевом Где где заканчивалось 3 дня Вот
This or what yes yes these 3 days that they
это или что да да вот эти 3 дня которые
wanted in 3 days and  they ran away and then they
хотели за 3 дня и убежали да потом
were broken Yes, because the
разбитые Да потому что
students In short, the country is in danger, we are
студенты Всё короче страна в опасности
taking students, I will take you You will
берём студентов возьму тебя Ты будешь
kill people
убивать людей
for Well, if they want to kill me, a person
за Ну если меня Меня хотят убить человек
Well, how are you? Look, they imprisoned you and they
Ну как тебя Смотри тебя посадили и
say so You  you’re running with these dudes, you’re
говорят так Ты бежишь с этими чуваками
running towards this Hakob and you’re not going to shoot,
бежите на этот Акоп и стрелять ты буде
I’m not soon, most likely No, why do I need you
не я нет ско скорее всего Нет зачем мне
And how are you? That is, you won’t disobey the
у А как ты То есть ты не ослушаешься
order. Well, you understand, Well, it’s impossible,
приказа Ну понимаете Ну это невозможно
you’re telling the situation, you’ll get up now, you’ll
вы говорите ситуации вы сейчас встанете
go to the front, that’s also impossible. Well,
пойдёте на фронт это тоже невозможно Ну
how?  look,
как смотри
wait, if they take me to the front and I
Подожди если меня заберут на фронт и
have to run, I will kill you if they
надо будет бежать я буду вас если вас
take you to the front. Why won’t
возьмут на фронт Вы же что будете не
you kill? What will you do? No, well, if
убивать Что вы будете делать Не ну если
I said at the beginning, if I  there is
я я сказал же начально если мне грозит
danger. Unfortunately, I
опасность К сожалению я
have to bring you and you have to
должен тебя привозят и тебе надо
attack others, this is in
нападать на других это тебе грозит
danger for you. Or you have to bring me and
опасность Или тебе надо меня привозит и
attack others. Why should I attack
нападать на других А чего мне нападать
others? I don’t understand listening to your
на других Я не понимаю слуша у тебя
order, the commander said, let’s storm
приказ сказал командир идём на штурм вот
this strong point, well  if there really is
этого опорного пункта ну если реально
some kind of danger that threatens the
какая-то опасность будет угрожать
Russian Federation, then yes.
Российской Федерации прям тогда да Ну
Well, look at these guys who
как Смотри вот этих ребят которые в
were brought to Makeyevka and who died there,
Макеевку привезли и которые там погибли
they died because they were
они погибли из-за того что там их
brought there because  danger
привезли туда из-за того что опасность
threatened the Russian
угрожала Российской
Federation No, probably, although yes, it’s possible
Федерации Нет наверно хотя да возможно
like that I’m saying I’m not a political
вот так те Я я говорю я не политический
person, I haven’t even read the Minsk agreement
человек я даже минские соглашение не
That is, you can be brought in,
читал То есть ты тебя могут привести
brought in like this, thrown somewhere And you
привести так типа кинуть куда-то И ты
’ll even be like an apolitical person and
даже будешь как аполитичный вообще ни
won’t even understand what  you were brought and
фига не понимать что тебя привезли и
where they are driving you, like shooting is
куда тебя гонят типа стрелять возможно
possible, but if they really
возможно но для если меня реально
call me up, I will study this topic as much as possible and
призовут я эту тему максимально изучу и
will build on the situation that
буду отталкиваться от ситуации которая
will be you will be such a philosopher you will
будет ты будешь такой философ будешь
say there the commander and the platoon says so
говорит там командир и взвод говорит так
let’s attack this  point And you’re like,
пошли в атаку на этот пункт А ты такой
wait, now I’ll push away from the
подождите я сейчас оттолкнуть от
situation, I’ll study the system as much as possible, yes,
ситуации максимально изучу систему да Ну
of course, well, I’m an ordinary soldier. You want
конечно ну я обычный солдат Вы хотите
me to be an ordinary soldier. Well, yes, an
чтобы я был обычным солдатом Ну да
ordinary soldier. And who will you be, not
обычным солдатом А кем ты будешь не
this? It’s unlikely that I’m studying to be a programmer and
этото Вряд ли я на программиста учусь и
I’m a programmer. Well,
я программист Ну
look, lization Yes  They’ll take you
смотри лизация Да у тебя и тебя возьмут
and they won’t ask you, my grandfather was in
и не спросят вот дед мой был во Вторую
World War II, 19 years have passed, they took a
мировую войну вообще 19 лет прошло взяли
simple guy, not a soldier at all,
простого парня вообще никакой не солдат
nothing But although I have, look at another
ничего А хотя у меня есть смотри другая
theory, if it’s universal  mobilization will be
теория если всеобщая мобилизация будет
Well, most likely the people will definitely riot
Ну скорее всего народ бунтует однозначно
in Russia Well, I think so because
в России Ну я так думаю потому что
realistically, well, if everyone is a student, for
реально ну если каждого будут студента
example, I’m 18 there, 19 years old,
вот мне например 18 там 19 лет
sent to the front for a special operation Yes,
отправлять на фронт на спецоперацию Да
as
как
it were, the People will riot, well, what kind of Well, and
бы Народ бунту ну типа какого по Ну и
because of this it  it just won’t be that’s all You’re a
из-за этого её просто не будет и всё Ты
programmer, what course are you studying
на программиста на каком курсе учишься
first year first year yes cool
первый курс первый курс да прикольно
water type college or university
водный типа колледж или Универ
university university How many bytes in
университет университет Сколько байт в
one kilobyte do you know how many bytes
одном килобайте знаешь а Сколько байт
damn this is ig is ig How many  a byte in one
блин это иг это иг Сколько байт в одном
kilobyte eight no not this is a bit in a byte
килобайте восем нет не это бит в байте
In and this is 1024 in my opinion Yes 1024 is correct
Во а это 1024 по-моему Да 1024 правильно
Yes then 1 this eg you say you as a
Да тог 1 это эг говоришь ты как
programmer should do such things How
програмист должен такие штуки Как сеч
good Ay it turns out that's how you
хорошо Ай то получается вот тебя как вот
look, imagine You were hired as a
смотри представляешь Тебя взяли как
programmer and  me as a programmer and
программиста и меня как программиста и
here we are sitting, launching missiles at each
вот мы сидим ракеты запускаем на друг
other, they tell you to run and they tell me to
друга тебе говорят бежать и мне говорят
run. Yes, you will
бежать Да ты будешь в меня
most likely shoot at me and I will  you most
стрелять скорее всего и я в тебя скорее
likely Yes, so the question is why
всего Да так вот вопрос ради чего ты
will you shoot at me and why
будешь стрелять в меня и ради чего ты
will you be shot by me or someone else
будешь застрелен мной или кем-то другим
for the sake of your country, so what for the sake of the
ради своей страны вот так в чём ради
country and you Why are you shooting for the sake of we are
страны а вы Ради чего стреля ради мы
defending our country, everything is clear to us
защищаем свою страну у нас всё понятно
That  yes, if they take me, I will
То есть если меня возьмут Я буду
understand why I am with you because you
понимать за что я тебя потому что ты
have pinned my country on me. And why will you
припёрся мою страну меня А за что ты
run me, I just don’t
побежишь меня вот этого я как раз и не
know, look at the main question. Do you
знаю смотрите главный вопрос Как вы
think the special operation will end well?
думаете спецоперация закончится хорошо
Well, for you, the war is clear, but if not this
Ну для вас война понятно да как не это
special operation  this is not a war for us
спецоперация это не война для нас потому
because if there was a war, we would have bombed you
что если была война Мы бы вас разбомбили
already, but we
уже а так мы не
can’t well well,
можем хорошо хорошо
why is this a special operation? Well then,
по что это же спецоперация Ну тогда ну
really Yes, if if Putin is therefore
реально Да если если Путин поэтому и
afraid to declare war because
боится объявить войну потому что
Zelensky knows what the Americans
Зеленский знает что ему американцы
told him If it happens  the war can hit
сказали Если будет война можете бить по
Moscow in St. Petersburg And if the special operation is
Москве по Питеру А если спецоперация
only in Belgorod And it seems to me that
только по Белгороду А мне кажется просто
people usually just won’t understand that’s all Yeah So
люди обычно не поймут и всё Угу Так вот
let’s ask the question how this
то давай вопрос как закончится эта
special operation will end Yes, how do you think that’s a
спецоперация Да как Как вы считаете вот
political person Let’s  if we look at the trends of the latest there de Well, of this whole special operation, the army came running got the stars and ran away Yes, she fled from the Kyiv region Well, look, you laugh, how political Yes, if you are not political, then Listen to a person who understands politics, and that is, in fact, she was knocked out from the Kyiv region, Sumy, Chernigov, they were knocked out from Kharkov, so they were knocked out of Kherson, they were knocked out from the Black Sea, that is, they sank your ship there  The
политиче человек Давайте если мы смотрим
flagship was knocked out of the island by the snake And now
Флагман выбили с острова зме Да и сейчас
your ships Tusya
ваши корабли Туся где-то там
are hiding somewhere there in Novorossiysk, that is, that
Новороссийске прячутся да то есть то
is, they are no longer patrolling essentially the
есть они уже не патрулируют по сути ту
territory where the fighting is there in the
территорию где боевые действия там в
Kherson region and so on,
районе Херсонской области и так дальше
that is, Everything shows that Russia
то есть Всё показывает к тому что Россию
is being thrown back  discards and discards
отбрасывает отбрасывает и отбрасывает
Ukraine every month receives
Украина с каждым месяцем получает всё
more and more and all the latest NATO
больше и всё новейшее натовского
weapons. That is, if we started in
вооружение То есть если мы начали в
February conditionally with Soviet scrap metal
феврале условно с советским металлоломом
and a little all sorts of man-portable air defense systems  were and
и немножко там всякие пзрк были да и
anti-tank, but now Ukraine is the
противотанковые то сейчас Украина насы
same Hamer themselves and so on
теми же Хамер сами и так дальше
Yes, all this and Russia was once the highest
Да всё это а Россия высшие когда-то
in Russian, in short, it is becoming less
по-русски короче у неё стаёт всё меньше
and less so the whole world is helping us,
и меньше всего так нам помогает весь мир
which in terms of GDP exceeds Russia by a factor of
который по ВВП превосходит Россию кратно
just like that  as a result, yes As
просто так в результате ти да В
a result, that is, Russia cannot
результате чего то есть нельзя России
win against the whole world, you know, because
выиграть у всего мира понимаешь потому
Russia does not have as much money as the
что у России нет столько денег Сколько у
whole world has. Yes, and the technology is backward;
всего мира Да и техники отсталая техника
Soviet technology is also a result of that,
Советская ещё и в результате того
Ukraine wins; how
Украина побеждает сколько это будет
long it will last is another question  but
времени длиться это уже другой вопрос но
as a result, Russia ter Russia will be
в результате Россию тер Россия потерпит
defeated and huge internal
поражение и огромные внутренние
political processes will go well there
политические процессы пойдут там хорошо
and the territory of Russia will somehow change Yes, the
а территория России как-то изменится Да
territory of Russia, look. As a result of
территория России смотри В результате
the defeat, you already have a lot of
поражения у вас уже идут очень много
different destructive such
разных деструктивных таких
state things, these are these
государственных вещей вот эти
national Battalions there, the Chechens have
национальные Батальоны там у чеченцев
their own national  the Tatars have their own battalion, the
свой национальный батальон у татар свой
Bashkortos have their own as a result of
у башкорто свой в результате
internal upheavals after the loss.
потрясений внутренних после проигрыша
So you will have a conditional revolution there, or
Так у вас будет условно там или
so, or so there will be fermentation, so
революция так Или так брожение будет так
Russia will break up into different states, and the
Россия распадётся на разные государства
national Republics of Tatarstan will definitely separate
точно отделяться национальные Республики
Bashkartastan
Татарстан башкартастан
the population of the Caucasus Let the population of the Caucasus find their
население Кавказа Да обретёт свою
freedom and perhaps Russia will collapse, also
свободу и возможно развалится Россия ещё
on a regional basis there will be the
по региональному признаку будет
Ural Republic Far Eastern
Уральская республика Дальневосточная
Siberian and
Сибирская и
that’s all I think Well, like it’s impossible Well
всё я думаю Ну типа это невозможно Ну
why look in the seventeenth year too
почему смотри в семнадцатом году тоже
Everyone thought it was impossible it fell apart that the
Все думали невозможно развалилось что
Russian Empire collapsed And I thought
развалилось Российская империя А я думал
you were in 2000 Okay  In 1991, I
вы в 2000 Хорошо я по В девяносто первом
also thought it was impossible that the
году тоже думали невозможно развалился
Soviet Union would collapse absolutely. What’s stopping it from
Советский Союз абсолютно Что мешает
collapsing further? Well  It’s unlikely It’s
дальше разваливаться Ну Навряд ли Навряд
unlikely that it will be very stupid so look
ли это будет очень глупо так смотри
stupid no Glu it’s good that Putin
глупо не Глу хорошо этого просто Путин
won’t allow it Well, Putin What about Putin,
не допустят Ну так Путин А что Путин
look Putin is nothing Putin is a
смотри Путин уже ничего Путин
political corpse, he can’t do anything, what the
политический труп он ничего не может что
heck is Ukraine shelling the Belgorod
он сри Украин обстреливают Белгородскую
region Putin Can it be
область Путин Может её
protected by Ukraine Well, of course  shki there if
защитить Украин Ну конечно шки там если
we have gained the Belgorod region If you
мы обрели Белгородскую область Если вы
have gained the Belgorod region Putin
обре Белгородскую область Путин ничего
can’t do anything to us, what will he do
не может нам сделать то что он сделает
next the question is that you have a power
дальше вопрос в том что у вас силовой
apparatus  is dying in Ukraine Well, I don’t know,
аппарат дохнет в Украине Ну не знаю да
yes. Well, I’ll say, for example, about Crimea, you also
Хорошо я скажу например про Крым вы тоже
can’t do anything with Crimea,
ничего не сможете с Крымом
you
сделать вы
can do what we did with
сможете что мы сделали с
Kherson. No idea, we went there, we went there. Yes, why?
херсоном Без понятия зашли туда зашли Да
Because Russian troops
почему Потому что российские войска
somehow came out of there, so it’s absolutely
как-то оттуда вышли так вот абсолютно
similar to what will happen with  Crimea will be This
похоже будет с Крымом будет Вот этот
Crimean bridge, why hasn’t it
Крымский мост почему его до сих пор не
been blown up yet? They showed that we can blow it up like
взорвали показали что можем взорвать так
this, but they gave it because
вот но дали пом те потому что по
all this
крымскому мосту будет вся вот эта
public, uh, Russian military, will be running across the Crimean bridge
публика ээ Российская военная бежать
there, in short, who knows where? Yes Or maybe they
туда короче фиг знае куда Да А может и
won’t let them escape Yes, the fact is that
не дадут им бежать Да дело в том что
Crimea is on its own Yes, when I cut it off from the
Крым сам по себе Да когда я режут его от
mainland again from Melitopol And so
материка снова от Мелитополя И так
on and they will blow up this bridge, from a
дальше так и взорвут этот мост будет с
military point of view there will be
военной точки зрения
nothing, no supplies for you there  you won’t
ничего никакие поставки вы туда не
be able to do it and that’s all, that is, Crimea without the
сможете деть и всё то есть Крым без
Crimean Bridge Yes, even without Crimea, yes, that is, the
Крымского моста Да и без Крым да то есть
question of Crimea is a matter of time,
вопрос Крыма так это вопрос времени
just a matter of time Well, I don’t know Well,
просто вопрос времени Ну я не знаю Ну
that’s your
это ваше
opinion, I didn’t challenge it  to each
мнение это я его не оспаривал у каждого
his own and so on Absolutely true Yes, that’s
своё и так далее Абсолютно верно Да вот
all, in principle,
и всё в принципе
remember at the
помните во
beginning of the 10th century when these
время в начале X века там когда вот эти
White Guard troops from the Crimea fled,
войска белогвардейские с Крыма убегали
so they loaded onto ships, so in short
так на корабли грузились так короче
they ran away right there, look at such
убегали аж там посмотрите такие кадры
cool footage, it will be something like
прикольные вот будет что-то типа
this  something like this will run in
этого что-то типа этого будет бежать
short on this on e Well, it’s realistic that
короче на это на е ну реально что в
somewhere to swim to Krasnodar Kragovo is
Краснодар гдето доплыть кра гово есть
obtained by estimate on the collapse of the Russian Federation and what, for
получается смете по распад российс а что
example, what unites you in
например что объединяет тебя в
Krasnodar Chechens in Chechnya and Buryats in
Краснодаре чеченца в Чечне и бурята в
Buryatia Well, you understand nothing Well, the fact is that we are
Бурятии Ну понимаете ничего Ну то что мы
people, this is already true Yes, well, that’s what
люди это уже на са Да ну вот что вас
unites you in one
объединяет в одной
country, I, yes, I don’t understand, for
стране я да я я не понимаю у Вас
example, the Poles are now in the country Mercenaries
например поляки сейчас в стране Наёмники
Yes, I don’t know the French there with
Да которые там не знаю французы с вот у
look, we have Ukra, Ukraine,
на смотри у нас вот Укра Украина
monoethnic,
моноэтническое
why should the Bashkor, why should the Yakum Chechens
зачем башкор тамм зачем якум чеченцам
live in the same state if
жить вам с вами в одном государстве если
they can live in separate states
они могут жить в отдельных государствах
and everything is fine?  carry out their policy
и все нормально проводить свою политику
Yes, you think they are feeling bad now, bad, and
Да вы думаете им сейчас плохо плохо А вы
how do you know? I know because I communicate with
откуда знаете знаю потому что общаюсь с
them. They are with you now only because the
ними Они сейчас с вами только из-за того
repressive apparatus does not allow you
что репрессивный аппарат не даёт
to disconnect and that’s all. Well, it seems to me that there are
отсоединиться и всё Ну это мне кажется
no more than a few. Well, tell me why
единиц не более А ну вот Скажите зачем
?  just from the point of view of myself as a
вот просто вот с точки зрения себя как
guy from Krasnodar. So why should the Buryats
парня с Краснодара Так зачем бурятам
be with you in the Russian Federation
быть с вами в Российской Федерации
instead of the Nevi Buryats having their own
вместо того чтобы неви буряти иметь свой
language? Well, it’s just such a proverb: one
язык Ну просто такая пословица одна
head is good, but two are better understood. That
голова хорошо а две лучше понимаете То
is, if the people collectively live  and
есть если народ в совокупности живёт и
improves his country and strives for the
улучшает свою страну и стремится в
future and so on, let’s take
будущее и так далее да возьмём вот эти
all these reasons that you named Yes, like for
все причины которые вы назвали Да как
example you and Ramzan Kadyrov How do you
например вы и Рамзан Кадыров Как вы друг
help each other develop no you’re not your
другу помогаете развивать нет вы не
brother don’t take different layers of society
брате не берите разные слои общества
Good good You and the Guy from Chechnya so
Хорошо хорошо Вы и Парень из Чечни так
how do you help each other develop
как вы помогаете друг другу развивать
the country? Well, for example, I have friends from
страну Ну у меня например есть друзья из
Chechnya as well. Well, I have friends, yes. Well, for
Чечни также Ну есть друзья да Ну вот чем
example, why do the Chechens need you
например почему зачем чеченцам вы нужны
or why do the Buryats need you in Krasnodar,
или зачем бурятам вы нужны в Краснодаре
mutual assistance to him?  I’ll call He’ll
взаимопомощь я ему позвоню Он мне
help me at some point I’ll tell him Well,
поможет в каком-то моменте я ему Ну а
what’s stopping you from calling if you’re in
что мешает звонить если вы будете в
different
разных
states, most likely the distance
государствах скорее всего расстояние
will get in the way one way or another, and well,
помешает так или иначе и ну таки
look at the distances. Wait, if he
расстояния смотри Подожди если он сейчас
lives in Buryatia now, so will he live
живёт в Бурятии так и он так будет жить
in Buryatia, distance  will not
в Бурятии расстояние не
change No in
изменится Нет в
the sense of not Change not Change yes to the fact Well,
смысле не Измени не Измени да факту Да
I don’t know, he
ну вы Я не знаю фактами такими
throws out such facts like Russia
раскидывает типа Россия
will fall apart, it’s stupid, in your own
развалится это ж глупо сами у вас сами в
head you understand that this is impossible,
голове понимаете что это невозможно
very simply  what What unites you
очень просто вот что Что объединяет вас
all, what
всех что вас
unites you, I will say this, what unites you
объединяет я я скажу так вас объединяет
now is the power apparatus. Since as soon as the
сейчас силовой аппарат Так как только
power apparatus cracks, as it
силовой аппарат даст трещину как это
did in the seventeenth year, as it happened in
было в семнадцатом году как это было в
199 Perm, there will immediately be Parat sovereignty,
199 Перм сразу будет Парат суверенитетом
discord, in short, yes, it’s happening. Well, that is,
рознь короче да происходит Да ну то есть
What unites  for example, Muslims,
Что объединяет например мусульман
for example, these Chechens, Buddhists, Buryats,
например этих чеченцев буддистов бурятов
and you don’t understand what type of believers,
и вас непонятно каких типа там верующих
non-believers, Orthodox, Yes, there are atheists,
неверующих православных Да там атеистов
agnostics, and so on, yes, what
агностиком и так далее да да что вас
unites you in one country, I Well, I  I’m
объединяет в одной стране я Ну я
inclined to the opinion that
склоняюсь та к такому мнению что
mutual assistance is no more. Well, what kind of
взаимопомощь не более Ну какая
mutual assistance, look, Moscow is pulling
взаимопомощь смотри Москва вытягивает
resources, that’s the same Dagestan. I’ve been
ресурсы вот тот же Дагестан Вот я
talking to guys from Dagestan for days,
общался с парнями из Дагестана днями у
they have oil and gas and they live in
них есть нефть газ а живут у них
wooden toilets, that is, they
деревянные туалеты да то есть бедно
live in poverty. Why is Moscow pulling money
живут Почему Москва да вытягивают деньги
out of  these
из этих
regions And they won’t pull it out so the
регионов А так не будут вытягивать так
money will remain in Dagestan and you’ve
будут оставаться в Дагестане деньги а вы
been to Moscow at least once in
были Москве вообще хоть раз был в 2005
2005, well  you know that in Moscow only the
году ну вы знаете что в Москве только
center is beautifully built
центр красиво отстроенный
[music]
[музыка]
but the middle class should be
но средний класс он должен
present and the middle class and Yes,
присутствовать и средний класс и Да
why look why, you can
почему смотри почему вот можешь мне
explain to me why, for example, people in
объяснить почему например э люди в
Dagestan, where there is oil and gas, people in
Дагестане где есть нефть газ люди в
Bashkortostan, where there is oil and gas, live
Башкортостане где есть нефть газ живут
worse than  people in Moscow in Moscow Well,
хуже чем люди в Москве в Москве Ну
look, this is a layer of society no more, well,
смотрите это слой общества не более ну
in my opinion, there is a lower layer, a
по моему мнению есть вот низший слой
middle layer and
средний слой и
a higher one, let’s take the middle layer in
высший давай так возьмём средний слой в
Moscow and the middle layer in Dagestan  the
Москве и средний слой в Дагестане живут
middle stratum in Moscow live the same, I don’t
одинаково средний слой в Москве я не
know how much the salary is now in Moscow, but
знаю сколько зарплата сейчас в Москве Но
plus or minus I understand, come on, the upper stratum
плюс-минус понимаю давай так высший слой
in Moscow and the upper stratum in Dagestan live
в Москве и высший слой в Дагестане живут
the same Well,
одинаково Ну
look, minus, plus or minus, no, no, there’s
смотрите мину плюс-минус не не надо в
a lot more money floating around in Moscow,
Москве крутятся денег намного больше
really, yes  that’s why the middle layer in
правда пому Да поэтому и средний слой в
Moscow is steeper than the middle layer in
Москве круче чем средний слой в
Dagestan Well, you have the same system and there
Дагестане Ну у вас же такая же система и
is no niche layer in Moscow, so look again
ниши слой Москве нет так смотри ещё раз
Dagestan is rich  oil and gas so in
Дагестан богатый нефтью и газом так в
which some resources are extracted
котором там добывают какие-то ресурсы
Bashkartastan in which resources are extracted
башкартастан в котором добывают ресурсы
Yes Why does it live worse than a region without
Да Почему он живёт хуже чем регион без
resources
ресурсов
and Bashkartastan, that is, without resources, yes it
а башкартастан то есть без ресурсов да
lives and worse, I understand correctly
живёт и хуже правильно понимаю ми
Dagestan with resources lives worse than a region
Дагестан с ресурсами живёт хуже региона
without resources because it  center Moscow
без ресурсов потому что это центр Москва
is the center of decision-making How is your
- это центр принятия решения Как у вас
Supreme Ra how does he live by
Верховная ра за счёт чего он живёт за
making decisions No by
счёт принятия решений Нет за счёт
making decisions after the fact yes possible Yes by
принятия по факту да возможно Да за счёт
making decisions about  Wait,
принятия решений о Подожди ещё раз
look again due to the fact that he
смотри за счёт того что он принимает
decides to take money from one
решение забрать деньги из одного региона
resource region, give part of the money there and
ресурсного отдать часть денег туда а
keep the rest for himself.
остальное оставить себе
Possibly, yes, why? Yes, look,
э Возможно да то зачем Да вот смотри
why do people in Bashkortostan and people in
зачем людям в Башкортостане и людям в
Dagestan who are of a completely different
Дагестане так которые абсолютно другой
nationality have a completely different Faith?
национальности абсолютно другой Веры так
so that they have a decision-making center in
чтобы у них был центр принятия решений в
Moscow and not, for example, in Makhachkala or
Москве а не например в Махачкале или в
Ufa. I don’t understand what you’re getting at now:
Уфе Я не понимаю вы сейчас клоните к
Russia, well, that’s right, I’m not
тому что Россия Ну полная правильно не я
asking you. Look.  if you
тебя спрашиваю Вот смотри если ты
say that it will not disintegrate there is no
говоришь что она не распадётся нет
reason I say why do these people need to
причины Я говорю а для чего этим людям
have a decision-making center
так чтобы у них был центр принятия
in Moscow if it is beneficial for them to
решений в Москве если Им выгодно чтобы у
have their own independence The money
них была своя независимость Деньги
stays here uh decision-making
оставались тут ээ принятие решений
came in Ufa in their national
приходило в Уфе в ихнем национальном
state in what  the problem
государстве в чём проблема
and the problem is that I do
а проблема заключается в том что я я
n’t even know how to answer you because
даже не знаю как Вам ответить потому что
nothing unites except the power
ничего не объединяет кроме силового
apparatus, nothing unites the power apparatus - that
аппарата ничего силовой аппарат - это то
is, look, a person from Bashkiria from
есть смотри человеку с Башкирии из
Bashkartastan doesn’t need you and you don’t
башкартастан ты не нужен а тебе не нужен
they need a person from Bashkortostan, people from Buryatia don’t need you and a Chechen, you understand. You have the same system, then we look, take a person from Khmelnitsky, for example, a person from Kiev, a person from Lvov, these are the same people, the same nationality, so take a person from Buryatia from Chechnya and from Krasnodar from Moscow these are different people, but if a Chechen lives in the Khmelnytsky region, you will live in Kyiv and in Lvov you will  in Ukraine there is no compact
буде в Украине нету компактного вот там
million Chechens there Yes, no, that is, no, but
миллиона чеченцев Да нету то есть нету а
there are some, this is the National Territory of
есть уних это Национальная территория
Chechnya, yes, that is, huge, yes There are a million
Чечня да то есть огромная да Там миллион
people Yes, there is Tatarstan 3 ml so the
людей Да есть Татарстан 3 мл так
national republic Well, I’m more important, well, do
национальная республи Хорошо я важе ну
you really think people live in poverty
вы думаете реально люди бедно прям живут
and really don’t  I don’t think I think that
и прям не счита Я не считаю я считаю что
they and they understand that they can live
они и они понимают что они могут жить
better if this money goes not to
лучше если эти деньги будут уходить не в
Moscow but to Kazan or Ufa Well, it’s logical
Москву а в Казань или в Уфу Ну логично
Well, no
Ну же не все деньги понимаете да Зачем
you understand all the money, yes Why, tell me, why do people in Kazan, Tatars and Muslims give money somewhere in Moscow? Why should people give money to Moscow? Well, you have the same system, you just have everything going in cues. Look, I’m a Ukrainian in Kyiv Ukrainian in Lvov Ukrainian in Donetsk Ukrainian is all Ukrainians So you have Muslims in Bashkortostan, Muslims in Chechnya  Chechens are a
мусульмане в Чечне мусульмане чеченцы
multinational country Yes, why should they
многонациональная страна Да вот Зачем им
be in a multinational
быть в многонациональной
country? I will also repeat that in my
стране я также повторюсь как по моему
opinion it’s just mutual assistance and revenue
мнению это просто взаимопомощь и выручка
and so on, you understand.
и так далее понимаете
I’m just imagining the EU. Bastan would
Я просто представляю ЕС Бастан бы
really
реально
separate like that, it already separated,
отделился вот так он же уже отделял
look after the revolution of 1917, the
смотри после революции 1917 года
Russian Empire collapsed
Российская империя распалась
Yes.  not yet 1st year there were two revolutions, the
Да не ещё 1м году две революции была
February one, then the
была Февральская потом
Russian Empire ceased to
ещ Российская империя перестала
exist and the peoples gained
существовать и народы получили
independence, and that is, the same
независимость да то есть и те же самые
Bashkor then the communists conquered them a little bit
башкор потом коммунисты их немножко по
again, reassembled them, that is,
завоёвывали снова пере собрали то есть
everything was held on bayonets In the ninety-
всё держалось на штыках В девяносто
first year, it fell off, look Why
первом году отвалилось смотри Почему
Kazakhstan can be free like this, and
Казахстан может быть свободным так а
Bashkartastan is related, here is Bashkor, the
башкартастан родственный вот башкор
Tatars are related peoples, and both those Turks
татары родственные народы да и те тюрки
and those Turks Why do you look at Kazakhstan
и те тюрки Почему на Казахстан Ты
normally?  Kazakhstan
смотришь нормально что Казахстан
Independent lives developing And
Независимый живёт развивается А
Bashkartastan how will they be
башкартастан как это они будут
independent And how much territory
независимые А сколько территория
Bashkartastan can you tell me Well, that is,
башкартастан не подскажете Ну то есть
Yes, there are, I don’t know how many
есть Да есть я не знаю сколько
territories there are, but there are a lot of countries, there are
территорий так но есть ку стран меньше
a lot of countries that have a smaller
есть куча стран которые По меньше по
population in Bashkartastan, how many there are,
населению в башкартастан сколько там
several million, in my opinion Yes,
несколько миллионов по-моему Да
the population is in That is, uh, but Iceland is
населения во То есть э а вот Исландия
300,000 Why Iceland can  be
300.000 Почему Исландия может быть
300,000 and its GDP per capita is
300.000 и у неё ВВП на душу населения
greater than in Russia, but Bashkartastan is
больше чем в России да а башкартастан
something different and the same in Ukraine
что-то не также и в Украине то же самое
just look Estonia, come on, Estonia,
вот смотри Эстония давай так Эстония
how many people there are, there are half a million Yes,
сколько там населения сть пол милна Да
people have no idea, and that’s with those who
людей без понятия и то с теми кто
left there for the European Union. There’s maybe a
выехали там в Евросоюз Там где-то
million left there, that is, it
миллион може остался да то есть
turns out it’s less than in
получается это меньше чем в
Bashkortostan
Башкортостане
and three times less than in  Tatarstan
так и в три раза меньше чем в Татарстане
why then are you surprised how
почему тогда вас удивляет как это
Bashkartastan will be free
башкартастан будет свободным
Regardless I won’t answer you like that right away Not
Независимо Я вам сразу так не отвечу Не
me okay okay how do I understand it Okay
я ладно окей как я это понимаю Хорошо
how do I understand it  I understand why that’s why
как я это понимаю почему вот почему
Bashkartastan you don’t see that this is
башкартастан ты не видишь что вот он
why for you Surprise I don’t
почему ля тебя Удивите Я не понимаю ну
understand well you know Everything in Russia is more or
понимаете У нас всё в России более и
less liquid work It seems so to you
менее ликвидно работа Это тебе так
Well look Bashko for example the
кажется Ну вот смотри Башко например
Kazakhs in the Soviet Union also
казахи вот в Советском Союзе тоже
said Everything is fine with us  Rabo Kazakhs
говорили Всё у нас хорошо рабо казахи
wanted to become independent became
захотели стать независимы стали
independent independent What prevents
независимыми независимыми Что мешает
Bashkor from also declaring
башкор также объявить
independence time time what is
независимость время время которое сейчас
happening in the world right now And what time is it now
происходит в мире А что сейчас за время
firstly there is a special operation  globalization of the
во-первых идёт спецоперация глобализация
whole
всего
world, for example in Syria, I don’t know, some kind of
мира например в Сирии не знаю какая-то
special operation war is called, well, the world
спецоперация война называется ну мир
is changing, you understand The world is always
меняется вы понимаете Мир всегда
changing You won’t believe it The world is always
меняется Ты не поверишь Мир всегда
changing now it is changing very quickly
меняется сейчас он меняется очень быстро
and will be even faster in the future, and so on
и будет ещё дальше быстрее и так вот
the contrary, these processes give them the opportunity to
наоборот эти процессы Дают возможность
get it faster
им э быстрее получить
independence, I honestly won’t answer
независимость я я вам честно не отвечу
this question. So this is a simple question
на этот вопрос Так это же простой вопрос
like, well, well, I think so, I think so,
типа вот ну ну ну я так думаю я так
as Tennikov said, I don’t give a [ __ ], so
считаю как говорил теньков мне поху так
look, the population of Bashkortostan is 4
чу смотри население Башкортостана 4
million 4
млн 4
million in Europe, there are a lot of countries that
млн в Европе куча стран есть которые
less just stupid less all the
меньше просто тупо меньше все страны
Baltic countries yes less ok ok I understand Not
балтии да меньше о'кей О'кей я понял Не
everything can be done Lithuania more I don’t know for
все может может Литва больше я не знаю
sure yes but there are a lot of countries less yes That
точно да но куча стран есть меньше да То
is, why can you imagine,
есть почему ты можешь представить
for example, one country with independent norms
например э одну страну независимой норм
But here’s what-  then Bashkortostan will be
А вот что-то Башкортостан будет
independent in my head, but the
Независимый в голове у не укладывается А
most important question I also wanted to
самый главный вопрос Вот я ещё хотел
ask is that you really talked about
спросить вот реально вы говорили про
Crimea, about Crimea, and the fact that you will take
Крым про Крым да то что вы там заберёте
Crimea there, something like LPR, well, how  you
Крым там что-то лнр д ну как у вас
understand You have Well, the population is really
понимаете У вас Ну население реально в
three times smaller That is, if
три раза меньше То есть это бы если бы
we were faced with China now lop lop
мы сталкивались с Китаем сейчас лоп лоп
Russia Yes, they are on As they say, I
Россия Да они на Как говорится шапками
’ll throw hats at us Yes You know what’s
нас закидаю Да Знаешь в чём
funny The thing is that they don’t fight with hats,
прикол Дело в том что воюют не шапками
really Well, of course.  for example, let’s
правда Ну конечно Вот например да
take Makeyevka too, so as to
возьмём тоже Макеевку так для того чтобы
kill 300 or how many of your
убить там 300 или сколько ваших этих
mobile phones there. They didn’t throw 300 of
мобили Зро наши же не кидали в атаку 300
our mobiles into the attack. They threw one
наших мобили Зро их так кинули одну
missile at them.  hars or whatever it was No, hars
ракету харс или что там было Не ну харс
it’s just on the cruiser’s arrival, or
это вот как раз по крейсеру прилете не
other types, in short, the point is not that. The point is
то другие типа короче суть не в том Суть
that there is a technological war already
в том что война технологичная есть уже
now, no tacos came out in pure Polyushko
сейчас нет тако вышли в чисто Полюшко
you are sotochka and on sotochka if you came out
вас соточка и на соточка если вас вышла
1000 we are all  already lost Yes Victory, that
1000 мы всё уже проиграли Да Победа то
is, you can’t throw your hats in the air Well, yes, I
есть шапками не закидаешь уже Ну да я
agree with you, but the staff are people They are
согласен с вами но персонал люди Они
also important Unfortunately, yes they are important Yes, but
тоже важны К сожалению да важны Да но
technologies are at war, that is, if  for
воюют технологии получается то есть если
example, the Americans give us satellite
например американцы нам дают спутниковую
reconnaissance Yes, and show us where one of you is
разведку Да и показывают где кто из вас
hanging out And you don’t have a reconnaissance satellite on
торчит А у вас нет спутника разведки по
ours and they are trashing you There are
наш вас и разносят
no questions And look, not yet, although there is no
Вопросов нет А смотрите ещё не хотя нет
question, you kind of want to run away from the
вопрос есть ты типа хочешь убежать от
fact that I’m torturing you Bashkortostan Yes, you
того что я тебя мучаю Башкортостана Да
know, yes a hundred  because Well, really,
понимаете да ста потому что Ну реально
if I were a political person, I
если бы я политический человек был я
would understand, I immediately laid it out for you, I say,
понимал бы я Вам сразу разложил я говорю
I’m a politician, well, just, well, maybe I’m not a
я политики ну просто ну может како я не
politician, just as a citizen. Look,
политики вот просто как гражданин Смотри
this is how you think, I’m in my head, I
вот как ты дума я в голове у себя У меня
don’t  fit Well, how is this possible?
не укладываются Ну как это возможно Вот
Just look, you live in Krasnodar,
вот именно смотри ты живёшь в Краснодаре
for example, you are closer to Azerbaijan
от тебя например к азербайджану ближе
than to Bashkortostan, the truth is to
чем к башкортостану правда к
p Look, Bashkor Turks and Azerbaijanis are
п Смотри и башкор тюрки и азербайджанцы
Turks, why do you
тюрки почему вот Азербайджан ты
normally perceive Azerbaijan as
нормально воспринимаешь
independent Well, yes yes And damn Bashkartastan
независимым Ну да да А башкартастан блин
And how will it become  independent
А как это он станет независимым
Bashkartastan, you understand this, well, I don’t
башкартастан понимаете это ну вот я не
understand
понимаю
how if we annexed Crimea, we
как если мы присоединили Крым
annexed it to  they are sung for tea
присоединили к поется они для чаются То
That in the Soviet Union, this Azerbaijan
тем Советском Союзе этот Азербайджан
had the status of a union republic So this is
имел статус союзной Республики Так а это
a republic within Bashkartastan,
республика в составе башкартастан
a republic within the RSFSR was yes, that
республика в составе РСФСР была да то
is, and that is why Bashkartastan has not separated
есть и поэтому башкартастан не отделился
yet and for you this is how they can And
пока и для тебя это как это они могут А
with Azerbaijan you understand normally
с Азербайджаном нормально понимаете если
if  they wanted to secede, most likely
бы они хотели отделиться скорее всего
this would have happened, but for some
это бы произошло но каким-то по каким-то
reason this is not suitable for them, look in the
причинам им это негодно смотри в
Soviet Union, that’s where they became more heaping
Советском Союзе вот де год стали куче
independent Republics VM for example or
независимых Республик ВМ например или
some two guys were talking One
тамм какие-то два пацана общались Один
says so Azerbaijan will be free
говорит так Азербайджан станет свободны
you so Damn if they wanted to
ты так Блин если бы они хотели
secede they would have already separated Well yes
отделиться они бы уже отделились Ну да
No well there were other prerequisites so it was
Не ну были другие предпосылки так было
there the KGB monitored everything yes and then she gave up
там КГБ монитори всё да а потом о дала
slack and  everything has gone to hell Well,
слабин и всё всё разлетелось к чертям Ну
now it seems to me that there’s more slack Now now there’s
сейчас мне кажется слабин Сейчас сейчас
more slack, look, everything is there now,
больше слабин смотри всё сейчас есть
then it wasn’t possible to disseminate information,
тогда распространять информацию не
but now everyone on the Internet
получалось а сейчас всё все в интернете
sees everything, communicates, everyone sees Damn  tough
видят общаются всё видят Блин жесть
Russia is going down, of course, of course, well,
Россия валит проходит конечно конечно ну
not Russia is not going down, well, really, well, you
не Россия не валит ну реально ну вы
understand. Now look, if
понимаете А теперь смотри если
Bashkartastan wants to secede, not
башкартастан захочет отделиться не
declare independence, and for
провозгласить независимость так и
example, Putin will say that we should
например Путин скажет что мы должны
send troops to prevent Chechnya from
послать войска чтобы там не дать Чечне
being independent there, Bashko will become Well, that’s you,
быть независимым Башко стану Ну это вы
actually  you You will go, for example,
вообще это ты Ты пойдёшь например
to kill the Chechens if they proclaim
убивать чеченцев если они провозгласят
independence, realistically, I will wake up later
независимость реально я проснусь потом
after such Well, it’s not so realistic, look
после таких Ну это не так реально смотри
again, it’s already happened  you will go to
ещё раз вот уже ж было вы пойдёте на
Poland if there is more aggression there
Польшу если там больше начнёт агрессию
if they start aggression Yes, but just
если начнёт агрессию Да а просто
to capture
захватывать
Poland again has already happened Chechnya Chechnya
Поль ещё раз уже вот было Чечня Чечня
declared independence in the
была провозгласила независимость в
nineties Yes it was yes Russia went to
девяностых Да было было да Россия пошла
war against it Now if now, for example,
войной Вот если сейчас тоже например
Ramzan Kadyrov declared
Рамзан Кадыров провозгласил
the independence of Chechnya Calm down okay
независимость Чечни Успокойтесь ладно
why okay Well, that's it, calm down,
почему ладно Ну всё ну Успокойтесь
really, someone says that, you're
реально вот кто-то так говорит ты
running away, you're disguising  You’ll go. For
убегаешь ты маскирует Ты пойдёшь Вот
example, they’ll call for the liberation of
например призовут что надо освободить
Chechnya. But I won’t go. Well, as a military man, I’m not a
Чечню Да не пойду я Ну как военный я не
military man, they’ll take you if
военный человек вот возьмут если вот
they throw everyone away for the sake of the unity of
Будут кидать всех ради там единства
Russia. Mother, you’ll go to fight in Chechnya.
России матушки пойдёшь воевать в Чечню
But no, all this. And you’ll think that it’s
Аа нет всё это А будешь считать что
right that your country is bombing Grozny.  for
правильно что твоя страна бомбит Грозный
example Well, most likely not. But why
например Ну скорее всего нет А зачем
bomb? Well, well, now you
бомбить Ну на Ну сейчас же вы бомбить
look at bombing, that is, when Kherson is
смотри то есть когда Херсон сейчас
being bombed now, you don’t have a question why
бомбят тебе не возникает вопрос зачем
Kherson is being bombed  Kherson is being bombed Yes, I didn’t
бомбят Херсон Херсон бомбят Да я не
follow this Yes Kharkov is being bombed
следил за этим Да Харьков бомбят
for example then
например тогда
I wouldn’t have put such a
м пое ставте такую
situation against you, it wouldn’t
ситуацию против вас вое бы на это бы не
have happened if NATO had fought us Yes, section
было Если НАТО воевало нас бы ли Да разд
without for now Russia is unlikely to support
без поки Россия вряд подержи
Ukraine I would have had support then a
Украину усь была бы поддержка потом бы
check would have been written out to  at the end and so
чек выписали в конце и так Дале
Dassia can’t stop herself And you burn on fire,
дассия себя не может зать А ты гори подж
give me one last question, I’ll
давай мне напоследок какой-то вопрос я
answer it, I’ll run away from where it
отвечу на него побегу откуда на Беларусь
was preparing for Belarus  an attack from where an
готовилось нападение откуда на Беларусь
attack was being prepared on Belarus I think that from
готовилось нападение Я думаю что с
Pskov
Пскова
Well, it’s logical Russia should have
А ну это же логично Россия должна была
attacked Yes, it’s not unlikely that Santo came
нападать Да не навряд ли Санто заходили
after all, that is, there are no more questions
вс-таки то есть всё больше нет вопросов
Well, in principle, if there is something else Let’s
Ну в принципе если есть ещё что-то Давай
not do something interesting  about Belarus so
что-то интересное не про Беларусь так
wki storm are normal people in your opinion
вки буря нормальные люди по вашему мнени
people Yes but they live in an occupied country
люди Да но в оккупированной стране живут
and the Empire look the Empire conquers
и Империя смотри Империя завоёвывает
peoples and throws them into conquering new
народы и бросает их на завоевание новых
peoples just like the Soviet  When the union
народов так же как Советский Союз когда
took over Ukraine Yes, our grandfathers were thrown,
захватил Украину Да наших дедов бросали
for example, in 1968 to Czechoslovakia
например вот в 1968 году в Чехословакию
to suppress democracy in Czechoslovakia, so
подавлять демократию в Чехословакии так
in 56 to Hungary in Budapest yes And
в 56 году в Венгрию в Будапешт да А
how old are you, how old is the question 41
сколько м лет Вам сколько вот вопрос 41
And if you are called up, you Sing
А если вас призовут вы Пойте
and I will if I still have you yes  I’m not needed
и буду если ещ буду тебя да Меня не надо
Why Well, if they take you Well,
Зачем Ну если тебя возьмут сда Ну да не
I’m not you Why Well,
я вас Ну почему Ну
look, I’m a programmer and you’re a programmer
смотри я программист и ты программист
If you  if you come to my country I will be in
Если ты придёшь в мою страну я буду в
the trench you of course And you will be me of
окопе ты конечно И ты будешь меня
course
конечно
definitely yes that is you get it Well
однозначно да то есть ты получается Ну
you will understand that you are an
ты будешь понимать что ты
occupier No well if Propaganda
оккупант Нет ну если Пропаганда
works like that in my head then I won’t
сработает так в моей голове тогда не
understand You are definitely a programmer
буду понимать Ты точно программист
Perhaps yes Or or you just know  you
Возможно да Или либо просто знаете те
did it to get out of the army,
поступил чтобы откосить от армии всё
okay, good-bye, wait
давай хорошо до свидания стоп ещё
a second, I’ll gain experience and we’ll talk to you again,
секундочку я наберусь опыта и с вами ещё
okay, read
поговорим давай хорошо Почитай
the tin, but it’s not interesting, this is a question
там жесть Да не интересно вот это вопрос
that we should be discussing with everyone,
который мы должны педалировать всем
why do
зачем
you need one  country for Buryats and Chechens to live there
вам в одном стране жить там бурятам
And so on there’s nothing else to do, because
чеченцам И так дальше так нечем потому
all it rests on is the
что всё на чём это держится это вот
Imperial Center, which forces everyone to
Имперский центр который силой всех
learn the Russian language and give money to the
да учить русский язык отдавать деньги в
Imperial Center so that the Empire, in
Имперский центр так на то чтоб Империя
short, makes its army there, that is,
короче там свою армию делала так то есть
this is very clear  example Yes, he is a man
вот очень наглядный пример Да он человек
living in Krasnodar, he does not understand how
живёт в Краснодаре он не понимает как
Bashkartastan can be free, how do
это башкартастан может быть свободны как
they need independence? That is, if we
Зачем им независимость То есть если мы
take 100 km from the Bashkan there  conditionally, this
берём 100 км от там башкана условно этот
uh Kazakhstan Kazakhs are independent Yes,
ээ Казахстан казахи независимые Да у
he does not have a question why the Kazakhs
него не возникает вопрос зачем казахам
need independence Yes, and here is
нужна независимость Да а тут уже
Bashkartastan as part of the Federal Assembly of the Russian
башкартастан в составе фс Российской
Federation, he is like this Why do they need
Федерации он такой Зачем им
independence, why, that is, a person
независимость зачем то есть человек не
cannot simply understand Yes, that these are peoples
может просто понять Да что это народы
enslaved by the Russian Empire Yes,
порабощенные Российской империей Да
which are still  they haven’t fallen away from it
которые до сих пор не отвалились от неё
yet Yes, in 1917 The first stage of
Да в 1917 году Прошёл первый этап
the collapse of the Russian Empire passed, so
распада Российской Империи так
Finland Poland Ukraine fell off there
отвалилась там Финляндия Польша Украина
Yes, independence became then the communists
Да независимость стала потом коммунисты
positions, including Ukraine and
позах в том числе и Украину и ещё
some others that became independent,
некоторые которые стали независимы
they restored the
восстановили там на части осколках
Soviet Union there from the fragments of the Russian Empire, yes In the
Российской империи Советский Союз да В
ninety-first year This was the second
девяносто первом году Это был второй
stage of the collapse of the Russian Empire,
этап распада Российской Империи
14 republics fell away from the Soviet
отвалились 14 республик Да от Советского
Union
Союза
and now there will be a third stage of the collapse of the
и сейчас будет третий этап распада
Russian Empire, then the Russian
Российской Империи тобто Российская
The federation is like an artificial country, so
Федерация как искусственная страна так
that is, there is no one. Here it is simply stitched together from
то есть нету Вот она сшита просто ту из
different republics Yes, absolutely different in terms of
разных республик Да абсолютно разных по
nationality, ethnicity
национальному признаку по этническому по
uh, absolutely religious,
э религиозному абсолютно по
regionally, people in Vladivostok and
региональному люди во Владивостоке и
people in Moscow have nothing in common in
люди в Москве не имеют ничего общего по
essence except propaganda and the imperial
сути кроме пропаганды и имперского
center, people from Vladivostok were more often there
центра люди с Владивостока чаще были там
in Japan and China than in Moscow,
в Японии и в Китае чем в Москве
subscribe to my Telegram right now
подпишись на мий Telegram прям зараз
Ovin and
овин а
popk more and more  YouTube Zaga us
попк це дуже и дуже YouTube Зага нас
through sgr in new ban and even more videos
через сгр в ньй бан и дуже багато вдео
I don’t show people at the moment I don’t show
не показую людям вчасно не показуе
information  about stream Tomu for this purpose
информация про стрими Тому для того щоб
mi Mali operational link ppi directly infection
ми Мали оперативний звязок ппи прямо
and while there in telegra okm video
зараз а пок там в телегра окм видео ще
schezh tsikava and korisna information and we
теж цикава и корисна информация и мы
are responsible for you trim postiyny
повинни з вами трима постийний
operational link
оперативный звязок
nezalezhno VD togo chi show you about it
незалежно ВД того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine write
YouTube Слава Украине пиши